

PROFILE

Computer science graduate from VIT, Vellore with 3 years of experience as a software developer at Bank of America. Have worked on multiple investment banking application with tech stack including Scala, Python, AMPS, AKKA, Plasma (in house reactive framework), Apache camel, Apache spark etc. Have acquired in depth business domain knowledge on Investment Banking mainly securities.

CONTACT

PHONE:

+91 7001015557

EMAIL:

avirup.nandi.14@gmail.com

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/avirupnandi/

HONORS-AWARDS

GLOBAL RECOGNITION SILVER AWARD GLOBAL RECOGNITION PLATINUM AWARD GLOBAL RECOGNITION SILVER AWARD GLOBAL RECOGNITION PLATINUM AWARD

AVIRUP NANDI

Software Engineer (Scala Developer), Global Markets Technology - Securities

EDUCATION

The Air Force School (Subroto Park, New Delhi) - X 2012

The Air Force School (Subroto Park, New Delhi) - XII

VIT University, Vellore – BTech (CSE)

2018

CERTIFICATION

Bank of America Machine Learning and Deep Learning

- Great Lakes

March 2020

Functional Programming in Scala Specialization

- Coursera

September 2019

Functional Programming in Scala Capstone

- Coursera

September 2019

Parallel programming

- Coursera

September 2019

Big Data Analysis with Scala and Spark

- Coursera

August 2019

Functional Program Design in Scala

- Coursera

July 2019

Functional Programming Principles in Scala

- Coursera

July 2019

DAT209x: Programming with R for Data Science

- edX

July 2017

Android application Development

-TIFAC-CORE (VIT University, Vellore)

March 2016

SKILLS

Languages

Scala, Ansible, C, C++, JAVA, XML, R, Android, PHP.

Data Persistence

ElasticSearch, AMPS, XA Data modeling.

OS

Linux, Windows

IDE

IntelliJ IDEA, Eclipse, Dev C++, Code Blocks, Android Studio.

Framework

Plasma (in house reactive framework), Apache Camel, AKKA, Apache Spark, TensorFlow.

Business Knowledge

Deficits, 15c3-3(d)(4), 15c3-3(d)(2), M3, Settlements, Client asset segregation, buy-in, Investment Banking.

Industry Knowledge

Machine Learning, Test Driven Development, Business Driven Development, Algorithms, Software Development, Scrum, Jenkins, JIRA

WORK EXPERIENCE

Bank of America (Software Engineer 1 A)

(August, 2020 - current)

- Real time Deficit and Extension data streaming to operational data storage and subsequent enquiry on the data
 (Have designed the data model with bitemporality by discussing and debating with various stake holders. Implemented the real time streaming of data with this model using actor listeners.

 Have worked with Architecture team to implement enquiry on the data)
- Performance improvement of around 600%
 (Have Implemented the segregation of data in motion and data in rest and leveraging this implemented change in the reactor system which significantly improved the processing performance)

Bank of America (Software Engineer 1 B)

(June, 2020 - July, 2020)

15c3-3(d)(4) regulation implementation
 (Have implemented reactor system and various other work flow modules related to this regulation and productionization of the same.)

Bank of America (Senior Tech Associate)

(June, 2018 - June, 2020)

- Real time data streaming from Inventory management (Picked up Scala and delivered multiple modules for the project)
- Kafka to AMPS migration in Settlements
 (Implemented bridges to source data from various sources using apache camel and pushing the data to high available AMPS)
- Work Item Management for controls (Deficits)
 (Implemented the theory of the work finding the operations user by integrating the application with the strategic platform using apache camel)
- Deficit metrics

(Have single handedly implementing and productionized a statistical Reporting RESTful application for deficit controls in Scala using technologies such as Elasticsearch, AKKA, OPS server etc. in just 2 sprints.)

• DR Strategy

(Implemented DR scripts using Ansible and demonstrated the same capability by switching to DR for more than 2 weeks)